# **KEVIN LONG**

Austin, TX

Phone: 512-975-0082 | Email: kevinjlong75@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/klong75 | GitHub: https://www.github.com/KLong75 | Portfolio: https://www.klong75.github.io/KLong\_Portfolio/

#### SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer. Graduated from the full stack web development program at the University of Texas in July of 2022. Bachelor of arts in theater and worked as a theater artist specializing in puppetry for over 20 years. At first glance coding may seem quite different from theater, however both are highly collaborative creative processes that revolve around creative problem solving in an effort to reach a common goal. Both endeavors require a focused group of people working together to build something. The tools and building materials just happen to be different. Thrive on creative problem solving and collaboration. Excited to continue my coding journey. Coding is not only a path to gainful and meaningful employment but also a way to further personal creative pursuits and make positive contributions to both the local and global communities.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6+, SQL

**Applications:** GitHub, MongoDB, Mongoose, Sequelize, MySQL, Express, React, Node,

Handlebars, jQuery, Bootstrap, Google, Material UI

#### **PROJECTS**

# MUSICOLOGY | https://github.com/KLong75/musician-networking-app | https://musicology-umekev.herokuapp.com/

- A MERN stack networking application for musicians.
- Role: Primary author and project manager
- Tools: MongoDB, Mongoose, Express.js, React, Node.js, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Material UI, bcrypt, JSON web tokens,

### Who Do? | github.com/truppeiner/who-do | who-do-austin.herokuapp.com/login

- A full stack social media type application that allows users to create and share events in the Austin area.
- Role: Backend database and data models | Frontend: Javascript
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Handlebars, SQL, MySQL, Seguelize, Express.js, Bootstrap

#### Movies R Us | github.com/KLong75/Movies-R-Us-KJ | klong75.github.io/Movies-R-Us-KJ/

- Allows users to browse titles by genre across all major subscription streaming services and link directly to a selected title on any streaming service that carries the title.
- Role: Javascript
- HTML, Javascript, CSS

#### EXPERIENCE

## First and Second Grade Teacher Austin Discovery School

8/2020 - 8/2021

Austin, TX

Utilized clear communication and critical thinking skills to develop and implement lesson plans for all subjects across two grade levels. Responsible for safety and supervision of my class. Teaching takes flexibility, adaptability, patience, multi-tasking, quick thickening, and a thick skin.

Key Accomplishment

• Successfully developed and implemented an innovative online learning system for virtual learning during COVID. This experience led directly to my interest in coding.

### Preschool Teacher Children's Discovery Center

7/2019 - 6/2020

Austin, TX

Supervision, care, and safety of a classroom of 12 two year old children. Such work takes flexibility, adaptability, patience, multi-tasking, quick thinking, and a thick skin.

Manufacturer 8/2018 - 7/2019
Calton Cases Austin, TX

Fabrication and installation by hand of interiors for custom guitar, bass, banjo, mandolin, and violin cases using foam, fabric, and a variety of glues. We tracked progress on orders using a Kanban board similar in fashion to those used by coding teams.

### Procurement Supervisor University of TX, Athletics Nutrition Center

10/2017 - 8/2018

Austin, TX

Inventory management, ordering of all food and supplies, receiving orders, supervising stocking of all items received, researching new items, communicating with vendors, supervising monthly physical inventory, customer service, etc.

Key Accomplishment

Implemented and developed an electronic ordering and inventory system.

# Project Administrator Dodge Moving and Storage

1/2017 - 10/2017

Earth City, MO

Inventory management, account management, invoicing, data entry, writing and researching contracts, logistical planning, cost analysis, bill collection, communicating with warehouse, dispatch, and drivers, customer service, etc.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Certificate in Full Stack Web Development - Graduated July 2022 University of Texas

Austin, TX

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Full Stack Web Development

Bachelor of Arts in Theater - Graduated May 1998
Truman State University

Kirksville, MO